https://marketview.co.nz/2018/10/31/privacy-policy/

Last updated: November 2, 2018
Marketview Limited (“Marketview” or “we”) respect your concerns about privacy. This Online Privacy Notice (the “Notice”) applies to personal data we collect on www.marketview.co.nz or any Verisk-branded website that links to this Notice (the “Sites”). The Notice describes the types of personal data we obtain, how we use the personal data, and with whom we share it. We also describe the rights you may have and how you can contact us about our privacy practices.
Marketview is the data controller in respect of personal data that we collect through the Site or that you provide to us. Our contact details can be found at the How To Contact Us section at the end of this Notice.
How We Obtain Information About You
We may collect personal data that you choose to provide to us through the Site, including, but not limited to, your first and last name, physical address, e-mail address, or telephone number, such as when you:
Fill out a form on the Site;
Sign-up to receive direct marketing communications on the Site;
Sign-up to a feature that we offer on the Site and you provide your personal data in connection with that feature;
Attend an event that we [or a Verisk affiliate] has organised; or
Communicate with us (for example, on a social media platform or by sending us an email).
When you visit our Sites, we also may collect certain information by automated means using technologies such as cookies, non-cookie-based tokens, web server logs, tracking pixels, and web beacons. Cookies are files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to identify your browser uniquely or to store information or settings in your browser. Your browser may tell you when you receive certain types of cookies and how to restrict or disable certain cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to use all of the features of our Site and may not be able to purchase products that use a “shopping cart.” You can order any product by telephone by calling Customer Service at 0064 4 472 1991. Non-cookie-based tokens are encoded URL-based identifiers that track e-mail click-thru activity or time-sensitive password reset keys and will work in scenarios where cookies are disabled or a session has not been initiated.
We may also collect personal data in other contexts that we will notify you of at the time.
Information We Obtain
Information That You Provide to Us
Personal data that you provide directly to us will be apparent from the context in which you provide it, for example:
If you fill out a form on our Site, you will generally provide your name, contact details and any other information requested by the form, such as the reason for your enquiry or your product preferences;
If you sign up to receive electronic marketing communications from us, you will generally provide your name, email address and other contact information, and your product preferences;
If you sign up to a feature on our Site, you will generally provide your name and contact information and any other information necessary to access the feature.
Each form on our Site varies in the information required and collected. In most cases, an asterisk (*) indicates the required information on a form. You may choose to provide additional information within fields that are not required.
Information That We Collect Automatically
Our web servers may log information such as your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located. The web server logs may also record information such as the address of the web page that referred you to our Sites and the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. They may also log information about your interaction with the Sites, such as which pages you visit. To control which web servers collect information by automated means, we may place tags called “web beacons” — small files that link web pages to particular web servers and their cookies. We may also collect information from your browser, such as your browsing history, and use it in conjunction with data gathered from forms and e-mails to help us understand and respond to your needs.
“Do Not Track” Signals
Your browser settings may allow you to transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to websites and online services you visit. Like many other websites and online services, we do not currently process or respond to “Do Not Track” signals from your browser or to other mechanisms that enable choice. Both we and others (such as our service providers) may collect personal data about our visitors’ online activities over time and across third-party websites.
Social Media Widgets
The Site includes social media functions, such as the Blog, Twitter, LinkedIn, and Facebook widgets. These widgets may collect information about which pages you visit on the Site and the IP address of the device you use to connect to the Internet. The widgets may also set a cookie to ensure the features are functioning properly.
Social media functions and widgets are hosted either by a third party or directly on the Site. Your interactions with the social media functions and widgets located on the Site are governed by the privacy policies of the companies that provide them. If you use any of the social media functions or widgets on our Site, we strongly suggest you review the privacy policies of the companies that provide those functions and features.
LinkedIn Members
If you are a LinkedIn member and you visit our Site from LinkedIn, our Site may use tracking pixels — transparent graphic images placed on web pages — which, in combination with cookies, collect information contained within your LinkedIn profile as well as your access of and interaction with the web pages that contain the pixels. Marketview works with LinkedIn to provide Sponsored Updates and advertisements to your LinkedIn news feed. If you complete a form on our Site you will receive Sponsored InMails in your LinkedIn email account based on your visits to the Site and your perceived interests. To learn how to opt out of Sponsored InMail, navigate to Privacy & Settings in your LinkedIn account, choose the “Communications” tab, and then click “Turn on/off Partner InMail” to disable Sponsored InMails.
Information That We Obtain From Third Parties
Information that we collect from third parties will generally consist of publicly-available profile information (such as your preferences and interests), for example from public social media posts.
How We Use Information That We Obtain
Information That You Provide to Us
We may use personal data that you provide to us to respond to your inquiry, for example, to contact you about your request, ask a question, provide announcements about products and future events, conduct surveys, consider your application for employment, and contact you for other reasons related to offering and improving our services.
In addition to the uses discussed above, we may also use the personal data you provide on our Site to:
operate, evaluate, and improve our business;
develop new products and services;
perform market research;
advertise and market our products and services;
determine the effectiveness of our advertising and marketing;
analyze our products, services, and websites;
administer the Site.
We use the personal data for the purposes described above because we have an identified and approved purpose for using the personal data.
We may also use the information to protect against and prevent fraud, claims, and other liabilities and to comply with or enforce applicable legal requirements, industry standards, and our policies and terms. We use personal data for these purposes when it is necessary to protect, exercise or defend our legal rights, or when we are permitted by law that applies to us.
Information That We Collect Automatically
We use personal data that we collect automatically through cookies, non-cookie-based tokens, web beacons, and other automated means for purposes such as customizing and enhancing our visitors’ visits to the Site, facilitating use of the Sites, collecting statistics about your visits to the Site, and understanding the manner in which our visitors browse the Site. We also use the information to help diagnose technical and service problems, administer the Site, and identify visitors to the Site. We use clickstream data to determine how much time visitors spend on web pages of the Site, how visitors navigate through the Site, and how we may tailor the Site to meet the needs of our visitors. We use the personal data for the purposes described above because we have a legitimate interest in operating and improving our Site that is not overridden by your interests, rights and freedoms to protect personal data about you.
We also use third-party web analytic services on our Site, such as those of Eloqua and Google Analytics. The service providers that administer those services may use cookies and web beacons to help us analyze how users use the Site. The information collected by the cookies and web beacons (including your IP address) is available to the service providers, which use the information to evaluate your use of the Site.
To learn how to opt out of Google Analytics, visit: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.
To learn how to opt out of Eloqua web analytics, visit: http://www.eloqua.com/about/privacy/opt_status/.
To learn more about the cookies that Marketview uses on this Site, as well as to control your cookie settings on this Site, please read our Cookie Policy.
Other Uses of Information
In addition to the uses described above, we may use personal data that you provide to us or that we collect for other purposes. Where that is the case, we will provide an additional privacy notice to you that describes the purposes for which we will use the personal data and our legal basis for doing so.
Information We Share
We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal data that you provide to us or that we collect on our Site, except as described here. We may share personal data you provide to us or that we collect on the Site with:
Other Marketview entities
Other companies in the Verisk group; and
service providers that perform services on our behalf.
We may share personal data with our affiliates for a number of reasons, including because:
You have requested information about our affiliates’ products and services;
Details of the other companies in the Verisk group, including the countries in which they are located can be found here.
We may share personal data with service providers that perform services on our behalf such as payment service providers, analytics providers, hosting providers and advisers. All service providers have entered into legally binding agreements requiring them to use or disclose personal data only as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with applicable legal requirements. In addition, we may disclose personal data about you (a) if we are required or permitted to do so by law or legal process, for example due to a court order or a request from a law enforcement agency, (b) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, (c) in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual fraudulent or other illegal activity, and (c) in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution, or liquidation).
Data Transfers
We may transfer the personal data that we collect about you to recipients in countries other than the country in which the personal data originally was collected. Those countries may not have the same data protection laws as New Zealand. When we transfer your personal data to recipients in other countries (such as the U.S.), we will protect that personal data as described in this Notice.
You may request a copy of the safeguards that we have put in place in respect of transfers of personal data by contacting us as described in the How To Contact Us section below.
How Long We Keep Information
The time period for which we keep personal data depends on the purpose for which we collected it. In all cases we keep it for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which we collected it. We will then delete the personal data, unless we are legally required to retain it or if we need to retain it in order to comply with our legal obligations (for example, for tax and accounting purposes).
Subject to any applicable legal requirements, we typically retain personal data as follows:
Personal data you provide to us through our Site: we keep this personal data for as long as necessary in order to respond to your request, and for a short further period in case you send us further requests.
Personal data you provide when you sign-up to receive direct marketing communications: we keep most of this personal data for the duration of our relationship with you until you opt-out or we do not have any contact with you for a long period of time.
Personal data collected for analytics purposes: we keep this personal data for a short period of time necessary for us to carry out the analytics.
Website logs: we keep Site audit logs, which may contain your personal data, for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose for which it was collected.
Your Rights and Choices
If you are located in New Zealand, you have the following rights under the Privacy Act 1993 in relation to personal data that we hold about you:
To request confirmation of whether we process personal data relating to you, and if so, to request a copy of that personal data;
To request that we rectify or update your personal data that is inaccurate, incomplete or outdated.
To request that we erase your personal data in certain circumstances, such as where we collected personal data on the basis of your consent and you withdraw your consent;
To request that we restrict the use of your personal data in certain circumstances, such as while we consider another request that you have submitted, for example a request that we update your personal data;
Where you have given us consent to process your personal data, to withdraw your consent; and
To request that we provide a copy of your personal data to you in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format, in a timely manner, in certain circumstances.
Where Your Information will be Held
Any personal data that we collect will be held by Marketview at
PO Box 25007
Featherson St.
Wellington 6146
and
Xactware Solutions, Inc (a Verisk Business)
1100 West Traverse Parkway
Lehi, UT 84043 USA.
Failure to Provide Your Information
In order for us to supply our services to you, we need to collect your personal information. You do not have to provide us with any personal information, however, if you do not do so, we may not be able to complete the services you may request or wish to engage with on our online platforms.
Updates to Our Online Privacy Notice
We may update this Notice periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal data practices or relevant laws. We will post the updated version and indicate at the top of the notice when it was most recently updated.
How to Contact Us
If you have any questions or comments about this Notice or any issue relating to how we collect, use, or disclose personal data, or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, you may contact us:
By e-mail at: info@marketview.co.nz
In writing at:
Marketview
PO Box 25007
Featherson St.
Wellington 6146
Comments are closed.
